Alexander Graham Bell Family
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1870-1922, n.d. (Box 102-142)
  - Alphabetical file (Box 127)
    - "B-Bz" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Bacheller, Irving
    - Baird, Spencer
    - Baldwin, Frederick W. ("Casey")
    - Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, Earl of (Box 128)
    - Barnard, Frederick A. P. For additional material see Container 213, Faber's talking machine, and Container 267, National Academy of Sciences
    - Barrows, Samuel J.
    - Bayard, Thomas F.
    - Bedwin, W. F.
    - Biddulph, Thomas For additional material see Container 321, Victoria, Queen of Great Britain
    - Billings, John S. For additional material see Container 179, Census, and Container 267, National Academy of Sciences
    - Bishop, William Henry
    - Blaine, James Gillespie
    - Blake, Clarence J.
    - Blake, Francis H.
    - Bliss, D. Willard
    - Boardman, Mabel T.
    - Bocock, John Paul
    - Bok, Edward W.
    - Booth, Evangeline
    - Bowditch, Henry P. For additional material see Container 221, Induction balance
    - Boyle, Charles E.
    - Brashear, John A.
    - Breckenridge, Mary S.
    - Brewer, William Henry
    - Brooks, William Keith
    - Bryce, Elizabeth Marion
    - Bryce, James
    - Butterworth, Benjamin
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Candolle, Alphonse de
    - Cannon, Frank J.
    - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
    - Carpenter, Frank G.
    - Cassini, Arturo
    - Cassini, Marguerite
    - Casson, Herbert N.
    - Cattell, James McKeen For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell; Container 271, Science; and Containers 285-287, Smithsonian Institution
    - Chamberlain, Joseph
    - Chester, Colby M.
    - Cochrane, Alexander
    - Condit, Charles L.
    - Converse, Charles Crozat
    - Cooke, Douglas A.
    - Cope, Edward D. (Box 129)
    - Cornish, Thomas E.
    - Coues, Elliot
    - Crane, Charles R.
    - Crouter, Albert L. E. For additional material see Container 184, Gallaudet, Edward Miner
    - Cunningham, William
    - Curie, Marie
    - Curren, Villa J.
    - Curtis, Cyrus H. K.
    - Curtis, William E.
    - Cusani, Confalonieri
    - "D-Dz" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Davenport, Charles B. See Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell, and Containers 274-285, Sheep breeding records
    - Day, David T.
    - Deland, Fred For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell, and Containers 185-187, Heredity
    - Deprez, Marcel
    - Doolittle, Thomas B.
    - Dudley, Theresa B.
    - Dunlop, John R.
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Eccleston, Marie
    - Edison, Mina Miller
    - Edison, Thomas A.
    - Edson, John J. For additional material see Container 267, National Geographic Magazine, and Container 270, Presidential inaugural committees
    - Ellis, Alexander John For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell, and Containers 201-203, Visible speech
    - Eustis, James
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Fairbanks, Charles Warren
    - Farquhar, Gilbert
    - Fay, Edward Allen For additional material see Container 179, Census
    - Fletcher, Charles R.
    - Forbes, William H.
    - Foster, John Watson
    - Frear, Walter F.
    - Frost, William G.
    - Fuller, Melville Weston For additional material see Containers 285-287, Smithsonian Institution
    - Fuller, Sarah For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell; Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell; Containers 158-167, Biographical information; Container 184, Gallaudet, Edward Miner; Container 193, Parents of Deaf Children; Container 201, True, Mary H.; Containers 210-212, Deland, Fred; and Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Furnivall, Frederick J. See Containers 12-14, Visible speech
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Gaillard, Alberic
    - Gallaudet, Edward Miner For additional material see Container 179, Census
    - Gallaudet, Thomas H. (Box 130)
    - Garfield, Lucretia R.
    - Garland, Augustus H.
    - Gilbert, Grove K. For additional material see Container 294, Lightning
    - Gilder, Richard Watson
    - Gildersleeve, Basil See Container 225, Langley, Samuel P.
    - Gilman, Daniel C. For additional material see Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen, and Containers 326-327, Wednesday evening receptions
    - Girdner, John H. For additional material see Container 221, Induction balance
    - Goodrich, Caspar F.
    - Gower, Frederic For additional material see Container 293, France
    - Gray, Elisha, re the telephone
    - Greely, Adolphus W. For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Greely, Henrietta N.
    - Greene, Samuel A. See Container 183, Fuller, Sarah
    - Gregory, Jean
    - Grenfell, Wilfred T.
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Hale, Edward Everett For additional material see Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Hall, Asaph For additional material see Container 267, National Academy of Sciences
    - Hall, E. Stanley
    - Hammond, John Hays See Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell, and Containers 326-327, Wednesday evening receptions
    - Harper, William R.
    - Harris, William T.
    - Hart, Albert Bushnell
    - Hay, John M. For additional material see Container 155, Tetrahedral tower
    - Henderson, John Brooks For additional material see Containers 285-287, Smithsonian Institution
    - Henry, Mary
    - Hill, David J.
    - Hitz, John For additional material see Container 179, Census, and Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Hodges, N. D. C.
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (1809-1894) See Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell, and Container 133, Peirce, Benjamin
    - Holmes, William H.
    - Horsford, Eben Norton For additional material see Container 133, Peirce, Benjamin, and Container 267, National Academy of Sciences
    - Hoshi, Toru
    - Howe, Julia Ward
    - Hoyt, John W.
    - Huggins, William
    - Hunt, Thomas Sterry
    - Hutchins, Stilson
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - Insull, Samuel
    - International Bell Telephone Co.
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - James, William
    - Janssen, Pierre Jules César
    - Jenkins, Charles Francis
    - Johnson, Robert V. For additional material see Container 267, National Geographic Magazine and National Geographic Society
    - Jusserand, Elise (Box 131)
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Kauffmann, Rudolph
    - Keller, Arthur H. For additional material see Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Keller, Helen For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Kennan, Emeline Weld
    - Kennan, George For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell; Container 156, Beinn Bhreagh; Containers 158-167, Biographical information; and Containers 326-327, Wednesday evening receptions
    - Kimura, H.
    - King, Dexter S.
    - King, Moses
    - Knapp, Martin A.
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Laemmle, Carl
    - Lahm, Frank Purdy
    - Langley, Samuel P., (2 folders) For additional material see Containers 285-287, Smithsonian Institution
    - Limholtz, Carl
    - Loeb, William
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 132)
    - Mackay-Smith, Alexander
    - Macy, John A. For additional material see Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Marburg, Theodore
    - Marconi, Guglielmo
    - Marsh, Daniel L. See Containers 158-167, Biographical information
    - Marshall, Edward
    - Maxwell, James Clerk
    - Maynard, George C.
    - McCurdy, Arthur W., (2 folders) For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell
    - McKillop, John
    - McKinley, William For additional material see Container 264, Longfellow Memorial Association
    - Meigs, Montgomery C.
    - Mendenhall, Thomas C.
    - Meredith, William M.
    - Merriam, William R.
    - Michels, John For additional material see Container 271, Science
    - Michelson, Albert A.
    - Miller, Samuel F.
    - Minchin, George
    - Mitchell, Silas Weir
    - Molineux, Edward L.
    - Moore, Montgomery
    - Moore, Willis L. For additional material see Container 294, Lightning
    - Morrill, Justin S.
    - Morse, John A.
    - Mulford, Uri
    - Muller, Friedrich Max
    - Munro, Dana C.
    - Murray, Ada A.
    - Murray, James A. H. For additional material see Container 3, Journal, 1885
    - "N" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - National Child Labor Committee
    - Newcomb, Simon For additional material see Container 221, Induction balance, and Container 267, National Academy of Sciences and National Geographic Magazine
    - Nichols, William (Box 133)
    - North, Simon N. D. For additional material see Container 179, Census
    - Noyes, Frederick K.
    - Noyes, James Atkins
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Ormes, James M.
    - Osler, William
    - "P" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Paine, Albert Bigelow
    - Pauncefote, Julian
    - Pauncefote, Selina
    - Pearson, Karl
    - Peirce, Benjamin
    - Phelps, Wilbur M.
    - Phipps, Charles
    - Pickering, Edward C. For additional material see Container 133, Peirce, Benjamin
    - Plante, Gaston
    - Playfair, Patrick M.
    - Pollock, Anthony
    - Ponsonby, Frederick George
    - Ponsonby, Henry
    - Ponsonby, Mary
    - Ponton, John
    - Porter, Robert P.
    - Powell, Emma Dean
    - Powell, John Wesley For additional material see Container 264, Motion
    - Prang, Louis
    - Pratt, Annie E. For additional material see Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Preece, William H. For additional material see Containers 269-270, Photophones; Container 270, Radiant energy; and Container 396, "The Photophone..."
    - Pritchett, Henry S.
    - "Q" miscellaneous
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Rantoul, Robert S.
    - Remsen, Ira For additional material see Container 267, National Academy of Sciences
    - Richards, Percival D.
    - Ritter, Paul (Box 134)
    - Rogers, William A.
    - Romero, Matias
    - Roosevelt, Theodore For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Royal Institution of Great Britain
    - "S" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Safford, Bessie (Mrs. David Dart Safford)
    - Sanborn, Franklin B.
    - Sanders, Thomas
    - Scott, Adam
    - Scudder, Charles W.
    - Scudder, Samuel H. For additional material see Container 271, Science
    - Selfridge, Minnie L.
    - Selfridge, Thomas E. See also Oversize
    - Serrell, Edward W.
    - Sherman, William T.
    - Sigsbee, Charles D.
    - Skinner, Robert P.
    - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.
    - Spencer, Herbert
    - Spottiswoode, William For additional material see Container 133, Preece, William H.
    - State Department
    - Sternberg, George M.
    - Storrow, James J.
    - Stowe, Lyman Beecher For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Sullivan, Annie M. For additional material see Containers 222-223, Keller, Helen
    - Sumichrast, Frederick C.
    - Swan, Charles H. (Box 135)
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - Taft, William H. (1857-1930)
    - Tainter, Charles Sumner For additional material see Container 221, Induction balance, and Container 269, Phonograph
    - Takahira, Kogoro
    - Tarbell, Ida M. For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Thompson, Charles F.
    - Thompson, Mary
    - Thurston, Robert H.
    - Tissandier, Gaston
    - Topakyan, H. H.
    - True, Mary H.
    - Tumulty, Joseph P.
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Vail, Theodore N. See also Containers 269-270, Photophones
    - Varley, Cromwell
    - Vogel, Leo
    - "W" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Walcott, Charles D. For additional material see Containers 285-287, Smithsonian Institution
    - War Department
    - Warren, John Collins
    - Warren, William F. For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell, and Container 133, Peirce, Benjamin
    - Watson, Thomas A. For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell, and Containers 210-212, Deland, Fred
    - Weaver, William D. (Box 136)
    - Welch, John C.
    - Welch, William H.
    - Wellman, Walter
    - Wells, H. G.
    - West, George N.
    - Westinghouse, Marguerite
    - Weston House School, Elgin, Scotland
    - Wettstein, Francis
    - White, Andrew D.
    - White, Henry
    - Whitney, William C.
    - Williams, Charles, Jr.
    - Wilson, Huntington
    - Wilson, James
    - Wilson, John M.
    - Wilson, Woodrow For additional material see Container 225, League of Nations
    - Wollaston, Charlton
    - Woodward, Robert S.
    - Young Mens' Christian Association
    - Unidentified
    - Telegrams, 1907-1911, (3 folders)
    - Correspondence to and from persons other than Alexander Graham Bell
  - Stenographic notebooks (Box 137)
    - 1877-1879, 1882-1884, (7 folders)
    - 1886-1890, (8 folders) (Box 138)
    - 1890-1892, (7 folders) (Box 139)
    - 1893-1895, (8 folders) (Box 140)
    - 1895-1896, (6 folders) (Box 141)
    - 1896-1897, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 142)
- Subject File, ca. 1870-1970, n.d. (Box 143-327)
  Correspondence, notes, newspaper clippings, and other printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Alexander Graham Bell Museum, Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada See Container 157, Bell Museum (Box 143)
  - Artificial respiration
  - Atlantic cable
  - Aviation
    - General correspondence
    - Aerial Experiment Association, (5 folders); (11 folders); (7 folders); (3 vols.); (2 vols.); (1 vol.) (Box 144, Box 145, Box 146, Box 147, Box 148)
    - Aerial vehicle
    - Aero Club of America (Box 149)
    - Aero Club of Canada
    - Aero Club of Washington, D.C.
    - Aerodromics, experiments, (2 folders)
    - Aeronautical Chamber of Commerce
    - Air mail service
    - Baldwin, Frederick W. ("Casey"), (2 folders)
    - Blueprints, (6 folders) See also Oversize
    - Book of observations, (2 folders) (Box 150)
    - Canadian Aerodrome Co., (2 folders)
    - Chanute, Octave
    - Curtiss, Glenn H., (3 folders)
    - Curtiss Aeroplane Motor Co. (Box 151)
    - Experiments and observations, (4 folders) (Box 152)
    - Gliders
    - June Bug
    - Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Kenly, William L.
    - Kites, (3 folders) See also Container 223, same heading; Container 325, Tetrahedral kites; and Oversize
    - Langley, Samuel P., (2 folders) (Box 153)
    - Litigation, (2 folders)
    - Ludlow, Israel
    - Myers, George F.
    - National Research Council
    - Patents
    - Research papers (Box 154)
    - Selfridge, Thomas E.
    - The Silver Dart, (5 folders) See also Oversize
    - Tetrahedral tower (Box 155)
    - Walcott, Charles D.
    - Wright, Orville and Wilbur
    - Miscellany
    - Printed matter, (3 folders); (5 folders) (Box 156)
  - Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada
  - Baddeck Public Library, Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada
  - Beinn Bhreagh, near Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada, (2 folders)
  - Beinn Bhreagh Recorder
  - Bell Museum, Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada, (5 folders) See also Oversize (Box 157)
  - Bell Room, National Geographic Society, Washington, D.C., (2 folders) (Box 158)
  - Biographical information For additional material see Containers 210-212, Deland, Fred, (7 folders); (9 folders); (4 folders); (5 folders); (8 folders); (10 folders); (1 folder) (Box 159, Box 160, Box 161, Box 162, Box 163, Box 164, Box 165, Box 166, Box 167)
  - Blind
  - Boston University, Boston, Mass.
  - Centenary of Alexander Graham Bell's birth
    - "Bell Telephone Laboratories," radio broadcast
    - Correspondence
    - Miscellany
    - Monthly bulletin, Nova Scotia, Canada
    - Printed matter, (5 folders) (Box 168)
    - Scrapbooks and clippings See also Oversize, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 169, Box 170, Box 171, Box 172)
    - Stamps
  - Contributions to knowledge (Box 173)
    - Astronomy
    - Aviation, (2 folders)
    - Deaf, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany
    - Observations and experiments
    - Physics (Box 174)
    - Race betterment
    - Radiophone
    - Sheep
    - Speech
    - Surgery
    - Telephone, (2 folders)
  - Deaf (Box 175)
    - Correspondence
      - A-P, (3 folders)
      - Q-Z, (2 folders) (Box 176)
    - Alexander Graham Bell School, Chicago, Ill. (Box 177)
    - Amateis, L.
    - American Annals of the Deaf
    - American Association to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 178)
    - American Asylum for Deaf Mutes, Hartford, Conn.
    - Arizona School for the Deaf, Phoenix, Ariz.
    - Arkansas Deaf Mute Institute, Little Rock, Ark.
    - Association of Parents of Deaf Children See Container 193, Parents of Deaf Children, Association of
    - Asylum for the Deaf and Dumb, London, England
    - Audiometer
    - Audiometer readings
    - Barclay, James
    - Bartlett Associates
    - Boston School for the Deaf, Boston, Mass.
    - Burke, Mary Anne, sister
    - Census, (3 folders) (Box 179)
    - Charts of deaf families See Oversize
    - Chelmsford School for the Deaf, Chelmsford, Mass.
    - Chicago Association of Parents of Deaf Children
    - Clarke School for the Deaf, Northampton, Mass., (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 180)
    - Committee on Classification of Methods of Instructing the Deaf
    - Crane, Cornelia S.
    - Crane, Frances
    - Crouter, Albert L. E.
    - Daily Eastern Argus, Portland, Maine
    - Day schools
      - California-Illinois, (2 folders)
      - Maine-Wisconsin, (16 folders) (Box 181)
    - Deaf soldiers
    - Deland, Fred, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 182)
    - Dudley, Lewis J.
    - Dudley, Theresa
    - Education of the deaf
    - Eliot, Charles W.
    - Farrar, "Arnold on the Education of the Deaf"
    - Fay, Edward A.
    - Fechheimer, A. Lincoln For additional material see Container 184, Gallaudet, Edward Miner
    - Florida Institute for the Deaf and Blind, St. Augustine, Fla.
    - Fuller, Sarah
      - 1871-1882, (2 folders)
      - 1883-1922, (4 folders) (Box 183)
      - Correspondence with Fred Deland
      - Horace Mann School for the Deaf, Boston, Mass., (1 folder) (Box 184)
      - Miscellany, (2 folders)
    - Gallaudet, Edward Miner, (3 folders)
    - Gallaudet Centennial Commemoration, 1887
    - Gallaudet College, Washington, D.C. See also Container 193, National Deaf-Mute College
    - Gallaudet Conference, Jackson, Miss., 1888
    - Garfield, Helen N. (Box 185)
    - Gault, Robert H.
    - Gehring, Marian
    - Gifts to aid the deaf
    - Gillett, Philip G.
    - Glove Alphabet
    - Gordon, Joseph C. For additional material see Container 213, Faber's talking machine
    - Greenock Articulation School, Greenock, Scotland
    - Hearing aids
    - Heredity
      - Articles, (7 folders)
      - Bell research notes, (1 folder) (Box 186)
      - Beinn Bhreagh Recorder, Bell's notes
      - Charts See also Oversize
      - Deaf relatives
      - "The Duration of Life and Conditions Associated with Longevity, A Study of the Hyde Genealogy"
      - Genealogical Record Office, Washington, D.C., (2 folders) See also Containers 213 and 414-432, same heading
      - General correspondence (Box 187)
        - Davenport, Charles
        - Deland, Fred
        - Fairchild, David G.
        - Langley, Samuel P.
        - Miscellaneous
      - "Graphical Studies of Marriages of the Deaf"
      - Heredity and deafness
      - Higgins genealogy
      - Hyde genealogy
        - Research notes, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 188)
        - Statistics, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 189)
        - Study (Box 190)
        - Writings
      - Lane genealogy
      - Lippit family
      - Martha's Vineyard, Mass., genealogical information See also Container 264, same heading
      - Printed matter
    - Hitz, John (Box 191)
    - Hudson, Alice J.
    - Hull, A. B.
    - Hull, George
    - Hull, Suzanna
    - Hyatt, Alpheus
    - Institution for the Deaf and Dumb, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada
    - Institution for the Improved Instruction of Deaf Mutes, New York, N.Y.
    - International Congress for the Study of Questions on the Education and Assistance of Deaf Mutes, Paris, France, 1900
    - Jennings, Alice C. For additional material see Container 175, Correspondence
    - Kiesel v. White controversy
    - King, Dexter S.
    - Langley, Samuel P.
    - Lansing, Emma S.
    - Lansing, Robert (Box 192)
    - Legislation, Massachusetts senate, 1867
    - Line writing
    - Lip reading
    - Lip reading for adults
    - Lippitt, Jeanie
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1850-1924)
    - Lodge, Oliver J.
    - Logan, James H.
    - Lyon, Edmund
    - McGowen, Mary For additional material see Container 193, Parents of Deaf Children, Association of
    - Mitchie, Edward B.
    - Mystic Oral School for the Deaf, Mystic, Conn.
    - National Deaf-Mute College, Washington, D.C. See also Container 184, Gallaudet College (Box 193)
    - National Educational Association
    - New Brunswick School for the Deaf, St. John's, Nova Scotia, Canada
    - Oissen, J. F.
    - Okie, Susan P.
    - Oral teaching
    - Parents of Deaf Children, Association of
    - Private School for Deaf Children, Washington, D.C.
      - Correspondence
      - Daily journal and school record books, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 194)
      - "Dictionary of Homophenes", (3 folders)
      - Examination tests (Box 195)
      - Exercise books
        - Adult class work
          - How to teach speech to the deaf
          - Line writing, (2 folders)
          - Visible speech
        - Bell, Alexander Graham, and pupils
        - "The Golden Touch," by Nathaniel Hawthorne
        - Illustrated story
        - Line writing (Box 196)
        - Miscellaneous
        - Student exercises
          - Bingham, Floyd, (2 folders)
          - Davis, E. S. (Box 197)
          - Hull, George
          - Okie, Grace
          - Radcliffe, Pierson, (2 folders) (Box 198)
          - Radcliffe, Sarah, (2 folders)
          - Van Rensselaer, M. (Box 199)
        - Visible speech
        - Written exercises
      - Miscellany
      - Printed matter
    - Radcliffe, F. L. (Box 200)
    - Reinhardt, Anna
    - Royal Commission on the Blind, the Deaf, and the Dumb For additional material see Container 184, Gallaudet, Edward Miner, and Container 205, Wines, Frederick H.
    - San Francisco School of Lip Reading, San Francisco, Calif.
    - Sanders, George, (5 folders)
    - School Board for London, England
    - Scudder, Samuel H. For additional material see Container 271, Science
    - Sexton, Samuel
    - Sign language
    - Society for Training Teachers of the Deaf (Box 201)
    - Spencer, Robert C. For additional material see Container 181, Wisconsin, and Container 184, Gallaudet, Edward Miner
    - Teachers of the deaf
    - Timberlake, Josephine B. For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell; Containers 167-172, Centenary of Alexander Graham Bell's birth; and Containers 265-267, Movie
    - Trade School for the Deaf, Boston, Mass.
    - True, Mary H.
      - Correspondence, (3 folders)
      - Tributes to
    - Visible speech
      - The Association Review
      - Boston University, Boston, Mass., 1877, (2 folders)
      - Case book (Box 202)
      - Convention of teachers, procedures, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, (4 folders)
      - The deaf (Box 203)
      - Japanese language
      - Miscellany, (4 folders)
      - Mohawk language
      - Nature and uses
      - Notebooks
    - Volta Bureau, Washington, D.C. (Box 204)
      - Account book
      - Accounts, general, (4 folders)
      - Conferences, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - Calendar
        - General, 1887-1960, n.d., (2 folders)
      - Deland, Fred (Box 205)
      - Experiments
      - Miscellany